NORMAN LO

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/norman-lo-05496674/

GitHub: https://github.com/NormanLo4319

Website: https://normanlo4319.github.io/Norman Lo Web/

Phone: (415) 706-8788 Address: San Francisco, CA 94107 E-mail:

lokman@mail.sfsu.edu

SUMMARY

Data scientist with several years of experience in academic research and data analysis. Experienced in data management and statistical packages, such as VBA, Python, R, Stata, MatLab, E-View, SQL, and Javascript. Currently enrolled in Berkeley Data Analytic boot camp for keeping up with the recent technology and best practices. Motivated to bring background in academic research and ability to build econometrics models with visualization to enhance decision-making and achieve company goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Stata, E-View, MatLab, Python, R, SQL, noSQL

Data Manipulation & Visualization: pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Plotly

Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB

Other: Git, Flask, command line

PROJECTS

Public Health Scores & Yelp Customer-Based Rating

- Analyzed the restaurants' public health score and Yelp customer-based rating in San Francisco.
- Pulled and stored data from Yelp API and SFDPH on over 2000 restaurants into SQL database.

Food Environment & Health Outcomes

- Analyzed the food environment and health outcomes over 200 counties in the U.S.
- Requested data from Yelp API and CDC public health data at the county level.
- Generated statistical analysis and visualizations created using Python, Pandas, and Matplotlib.

Informational Policy Improves Consumers' Choice for Healthier Food

- Analyzed how market information help customers choose healthier food option.
- Applied econometric techniques and built statistical models using Stata and R.

EXPERIENCE

Student Equity Economics Advisor, City College of San Francisco	(2017 – present)
Adjunct Faculty, DVC, SFSU, USF, CCSF, Metro. State University	(2015 – present)
Native English ESL Teacher, South Korea	(2010 - 2013)
Merchandising Manager, First Global International Ltd, Hong Kong	(2007 - 2010)
Senior Merchandiser, Hallmark Cards Corp, Hong Kong	(2005 - 2007)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: U.C. Berkeley Extension, San Francisco

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programing skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

M.A. in Economics: San Francisco State University, San Francisco **B.A. in Economics:** San Francisco State University, San Francisco